# **BRANDON MAX**

WWW.BRANDONMAX.NET BMAX1337@GMAIL.COM (248) 756-1134

# SUMMARY

Successful, young, and effective web developer with over 5 years of professional experience. Projects and assignments always completed on or before deadline. Excellent people skills and can work collaboratively in a team setting. Also self motivated and can work independently. Available for immediate placement.

# COMPUTER SKILLS

•	PHP	•	HTML	•	CSS	•	jQuery
			· · · · · —				J ~ /

SQL
JavaScript
Android
Ruby On Rails
Linux
AJAX

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Backend Developer Intern**

May 2015 - August 2015

Adobe - http://behance.net

- Refactored 20,000 lines of code over three months
- Localized more than 50% of the website so that it is international in 13 languages
- Made code testable using dependency injection and PHPUnit mocking
- Developed an internal tool for showing statistics on different projects

# **Engineering Intern**

June 2014 - August 2014

Barracuda Networks - http://copy.com

- Intern developer fixing bugs and adding new features to http://copy.com
- Cost saving development such as adding a bandwidth limit feature for the cloud
- Provided technical support for usability issues and critical site problems

# Freelance Web Developer

December 2013 - Present

Brandon Max - http://brandonmax.net

- Object Oriented PHP combined with SQL to create phenomenal Content Management Systems
- Most projects incorporated Smarty Template system
- Worked with teams of producers and designers to push major site changes

#### **EDUCATION**

Michigan State University - East Lansing, MI GPA 3.7 Sept. 2012 - Present

BS of Computer Science, Business Specialization, (degree expected Dec. 2016)

Oakland Community College - GPA 3.9

Associates Degree. Waterford, MI

Sept. 2012 - Dec. 2013

### HONORS & ACHEIVEMENTS & OTHER ACTIVITIES

Association of Computing Machinery (ACM) Executive Board Corporate Relations

Dean's List College of Engineering

Honors College Michigan State University

CONNECT

LinkedIn - http://www.linkedin.com/in/brandonmax

GitHub - http://www.github.com/bmax

Portfolio - http://www.brandonmax.net